<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sumesh Premraj's Homepage</title><link>https://sumesh.work/</link><description>Recent content on Sumesh Premraj's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 12:40:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sumesh.work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamically pick Jenkins slave in the same AWS region</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/dynamically-pick-jenkins-slave-in-the-same-aws-region/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 12:40:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/dynamically-pick-jenkins-slave-in-the-same-aws-region/</guid><description>As part of efforts to shore up security, I worked on moving from a single Jenkins master to a distributed setup with a slave in each AWS region. This might help if you use a cloud provider from Amazon, Google GCP or similar, and want to do the same.
Jenkins has a great plugin ecosystem, and we can use the Groovy Label Assignment plugin to make Jenkins pick the local slave automatically.</description></item><item><title>My setup</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/my-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 16:40:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/my-setup/</guid><description>Last updated: 08 Nov, 2021
Hardware
Operating System
Favorite software and customizations
Website
Photography
Hardware My work machine is a Macbook Pro 2019, and I have mixed feelings about it - love its sleek design, hate the mess of connectors. I have a dual 24&amp;quot; monitor setup at work, and a single 24&amp;quot; screen at home. My work is a mix of development and operations, so most of my time is spent within a code editor, a terminal, browser, and a music player.</description></item><item><title>Fixing undetected resolution in a multi-monitor Linux setup</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/fixing-undetected-resolution-in-a-multi-monitor-linux-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 06:40:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/fixing-undetected-resolution-in-a-multi-monitor-linux-setup/</guid><description>After upgrading to Fedora, I was unable to run my Dell laptop on a dock connected to two monitors properly. One of the screens would refuse to run at its maximum resolution.
It took me a while, but adding the resolution manually with xrandr and playing around with X configuration files fixed the issue.
Adding new resolution with xrandr Run xrandrto identify the screens by name. Note these names, they&amp;rsquo;ll be used in X conf files and for xrandr commands later.</description></item><item><title>Installing Arch Linux from scratch</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/installing-arch-linux-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 14:40:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/installing-arch-linux-from-scratch/</guid><description>This is a dump of commands I used, for future reference. Ideallym this should be an Ansible playbook or something to make it automated.
There&amp;rsquo;s more than one way to skin a cat, of course, but here&amp;rsquo;s my way:
using WiFi throughout the install a system with an existing Linux install I prefer zsh over bash I also prefer GNOME3 for its ease of use, although i3 is pretty nice too You can read more about my setup and tools I use.</description></item><item><title>Migrating to a new VPS - notes and command reference</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/migrating-to-a-new-vps-notes-and-command-reference/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:40:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/migrating-to-a-new-vps-notes-and-command-reference/</guid><description>I tried to setup this site on my VPS late at night. Sleepiness lead to stupidity and I ended up breaking various things on my site, that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite restore. Frustration eventually gave way, and I decided to set up a fresh VPS and finally make the move to nginx webserver. Previously, Apache2 tweaked for low memory was used, but it was still poor.
VPS migration can be fast and easy when done properly.</description></item><item><title>Directi interview experience</title><link>https://sumesh.work/blog/directi-interview-experience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 19:00:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sumesh.work/blog/directi-interview-experience/</guid><description>Directi, one of the highest paying Indian companies(with a tough interview process to match) had a recruitment drive on our campus (MSRIT, Bangalore) for the post of operations engineer - which is a mix of coding, deployment, monitoring and troubleshooting. A few friends asked what preparation I did, questions asked in the interview etc, so I&amp;rsquo;m writing it down here instead of answering individually. I hope it will help you in preparing for interviews in general, or Directi in particular :)</description></item></channel></rss>